Guide to the World Council of Churches Records
Yale University Divinity School Library
World Council of Churches Records
1927-2002
RG 162
Yale University Divinity School Library
33.5
(71 boxes)
This collection is primarily printed and typescript material that documents the formation of the World Council of Churches and its program activities. Monographs with distinctive titles and authors, which were at one time part of this record group, have now been removed and added as individual items in the Yale online catalog. The World Council of Churches is an ecumenical organization that was founded in 1948 in Amsterdam. It developed out of two other organizations, the Life and Work Movement, which concentrated on the practical activities of the churches, and the Faith and Order Movement, which focused on the beliefs and organization of the churches and the problems involved in their possible reunion.
World Council of Churches
Conditions Governing Access
Open to qualified researchers.
Biographical / Historical
The World Council of Churches is an ecumenical organization that was founded in 1948 in Amsterdam. It developed out of two other organizations, the Life and Work Movement, which concentrated on the practical activities of the churches, and the Faith and Order Movement, which focused on the beliefs and organization of the churches and the problems involved in their possible reunion. In 1937 the Faith and Order Conference at Edinburgh and the Life and Work Conference at Oxford accepted the plan to create one council. A conference of church leaders met in 1938 in Utrecht, The Netherlands, to prepare a constitution; but World War II intervened, and the first assembly of the WCC could not be held until 1948. In 1961 the International Missionary Council united with the WCC.
Scope and Contents
I. WCC in Process of Formation
II. Major Assemblies
III. Executive and Central Committee Meetings
IV. Program Divisions, Commissions, Departments
V. Miscellaneous Publications
VI. Related Organizations
This collection was at one time an open collection for all World Council of Churches publications in pamphlet or typescript format. Pamphlets with distinctive titles and authors are now added to the Yale online catalog.
Arrangement
I. WCC in Process of Formation
II. Major Assemblies
III. Executive and Central Committee Meetings
IV. Program Divisions, Commissions, Departments
V. Miscellaneous Publications
VI. Related Organizations
Ecumenical movement; World Council of Churches
- WCC in Process of Formation (1937-1948), Series I
  Scope and Contents
  The Constituent Committee of Fourteen was created by World Conference on Faith and Order and Universal Christian Council for Life and Work. For later editions of the Assembly Commission papers and other study papers, see Amsterdam Assembly materials in Series II.
  - Constituent Committee of Fourteen
    - Oxford Conference on Church, Community and State, 1937 (Box 47, Folder 316A)
    - Minutes, memoranda, invitations to church bodies, 1937-1938 (Box 47, Folder 317)
    - Responses from church bodies, 1938 (Box 47, Folder 318)
    - Meetings of North American members of Committee of Fourteen, 1937-1939 (Box 47, Folder 319)
    - Joint Work of Commissions on Life and Work and Faith and Order (American) - Publicity brochures, 1941, n.d. (Box 47, Folder 319A)
    - North American Ecumenical Conference, 1941 (Box 47, Folder 319B)
  - Utrecht Conference, 1938 May 9-13
    - Program, proceedings, statement, 1938 (Box 47, Folder 320)
    - Report to Conference, 1938 (Box 47, Folder 321)
    - Memoranda No. 1-5, 7, 1938 (Box 47, Folder 322)
  - Provisional Committee
    - Minutes, memoranda, reports, 1938-1948, n.d. (Box 47, Folder 323 -327)
    - Meetings of the members of the Provisional Committee, 1939-1947 (Box 47, Folder 328-220)
  - Preparatory Material
    - Papers regarding "Ethical Reality and Function of the Church" (Study Department of the University Christian Council for Life and Work, under the auspices of the WCC), 1940-1941 (Box 1, Folder 1)
    - Papers regarding "Ethical Reality and Function of the Church", 1942 (Box 1, Folder 2)
    - Papers regarding "Ethical Reality and Function of the Church", 1943-1944 (Box 1, Folder 3)
    - Miscellaneous Preparatory Material (Study Department Papers), 1938-1940 (Box 1, Folder 4)
    - Miscellaneous Preparatory Material, 1940-1942 (Box 1, Folder 5)
    - Miscellaneous Preparatory Material, 1943-1946 (Box 1, Folder 6)
    - (incl. "Man's Disorder and God's Design", 1948), 1947-1948 (Box 2, Folder 7)
  - Assembly Commissions
    - Commission I
      - "The Universal Church in God's Design", 1946-1948 (Box 2, Folder 8-10)
    - Commission II
      - "God's Design and Man's Witness", 1946-1948 (Box 2, Folder 11-13)
    - Commission III
      - "The Church and the Disorder in Society", 1947-1948 (Box 3, Folder 14-16)
    - Commission IV
      - "The Church and International Affairs", 1947 (Box 3, Folder 17)
  - Administrative Committee
    - Minutes, memoranda, reports, 1938-1939 (Box 48, Folder 331)
    - Minutes, memoranda, reports, 1946-1948 (Box 48, Folder 332)
- Major Assemblies, Series II
  - First Assembly, Amsterdam
    - Preliminary Material, 1948 (Box 4, Folder 18)
    - Preliminary Pamphlets, 1948 (Box 4, Folder 19)
    - Agendas and Directory, 1948 (Box 4, Folder 20)
    - Handbooks, 1948 (Box 4, Folder 21)
    - Daily Sessions: August 22, 1948 (Box 4, Folder 22)
    - Daily Sessions: August 23, 1948 (Box 5, Folder 23)
    - Daily Sessions: August 24, 1948 (Box 5, Folder 24)
    - Daily Sessions: August 25, 1948 (Box 5, Folder 25)
    - Daily Sessions: August 26, 1948 (Box 5, Folder 26)
    - Daily Sessions: August 27, 1948 (Box 5, Folder 27)
    - Daily Sessions: August 28-29, 1948 (Box 5, Folder 28)
    - Daily Sessions: August 30, 1948 (Box 5, Folder 29)
    - Daily Sessions: August 1, 1948 (Box 5, Folder 30)
    - Daily Sessions: September 1-2, 1948 (Box 5, Folder 31)
    - Daily Sessions: September 3, 1948 (Box 6, Folder 32)
    - Daily Sessions: September 4, 1948 (Box 6, Folder 33)
    - Undated, 1948 (Box 6, Folder 34)
    - Reports from Youth Delegates, 1948 (Box 6, Folder 35)
    - Press Releases: August 22-25, 1948 (Box 6, Folder 36)
    - Press Releases: August 27-31, 1948 (Box 6, Folder 37)
    - Press Releases: September 1-4, 1948 (Box 6, Folder 38)
    - Concluding Materials, 1948 (Box 6, Folder 39)
    - Decisions, Constitution and Miscellaneous Publications, 1948 (Box 6, Folder 40)
    - Reports and Inquiries, 1948 (Box 6, Folder 41)
    - Miscellaneous publications and press releases, 1948 (Box 69, Folder 474)
    - Newspaper articles, 1948 (Box 69, Folder 476)
    - Articles and papers, 1948 (Box 69, Folder 476)
  - Second Assembly, Evanston
    - Preparatory Studies, 1954 (Box 7, Folder 42)
    - "The First Six Years", 1954 (Box 7, Folder 43)
    - Preparatory Workbooks, 1954 (Box 7, Folder 44)
    - Preparatory Information, 1954 (Box 7, Folder 45)
    - Daily Sessions: August 15, 1954 (Box 7, Folder 46)
    - Daily Sessions: August 16, 1954 (Box 7, Folder 47)
    - Daily Sessions: August 17, 1954 (Box 7, Folder 48)
    - Daily Sessions: August 18-19, 1954 (Box 8, Folder 49)
    - Daily Sessions: August 20, 1954 (Box 8, Folder 50)
    - Daily Sessions: August 21, 1954 (Box 8, Folder 51)
    - Daily Sessions: August 22-23, 1954 (Box 8, Folder 52)
    - Daily Sessions: August 24-25, 1954 (Box 8, Folder 53)
    - Daily Sessions: August 26, 1954 (Box 8, Folder 54)
    - Daily Sessions: August 27, 1954 (Box 8, Folder 55)
    - Daily Sessions: August 28, 1954 (Box 8, Folder 56)
    - Daily Sessions: August 29, 1954 (Box 9, Folder 57)
    - Daily Sessions: August 30-31, 1954 (Box 9, Folder 58)
    - I. Faith and Order Documents, 1954 (Box 9, Folder 59)
    - II. Evangelism Documents, 1954 (Box 9, Folder 60)
    - III. Social Questions Documents, 1954 (Box 9, Folder 61)
    - IV. International Affairs Documents, 1954 (Box 9, Folder 62)
    - V. Intergroup Relations Documents, 1954 (Box 9, Folder 63)
    - VI. The Laity Documents, 1954 (Box 10, Folder 64)
    - Main Theme Documents, 1954 (Box 10, Folder 65)
    - General Policy (1) Reports, 1954 (Box 10, Folder 66)
    - Division of Studies (2) Reports, 1954 (Box 10, Folder 67)
    - Ecumenical Action (3) Reports, 1954 (Box 10, Folder 68)
    - Committee on Refugees (4) Reports, 1954 (Box 10, Folder 69)
    - Information Department (5) Report, 1954 (Box 10, Folder 70)
    - Finance Committee (6) Report, 1954 (Box 10, Folder 71)
    - International Affairs (7) Report, 1954 (Box 10, Folder 72)
    - Nominations and Credentials Report, 1954 (Box 10, Folder 73)
    - Miscellaneous Statements, 1954 (Box 10, Folder 74)
    - On Official Files, 1954 (Box 10, Folder 75)
    - Special Programs, incl. Accredited Visitors Program, 1954 (Box 10, Folder 76)
    - Daily Bulletins, 1954 (Box 11, Folder 77)
    - News Reports, 1954 (Box 11, Folder 78)
    - "Selected Addresses", 1954 (Box 11, Folder 79)
    - Reports - WCC generated, 1954 (Box 11A, Folder 80)
    - Reports - other, 1954 (Box 11A, Folder 81)
    - Concluding Reports, incl. Einerlei Hoffnung Eurer Berufung, 1954 (Box 11A, Folder 82)
    - Study Guide, 1954 (Box 67, Folder 460)
  - Third Assembly, New Delhi
    - Preliminary Correspondence, 1961 (Box 12, Folder 83)
    - Preparatory Materials, 1961 (Box 12, Folder 84)
    - Documents 1, 38, 45-53, Undated (Box 12, Folder 85)
    - Documents 54-63, Undated (Box 12, Folder 86)
    - Documents 64-80, Undated (Box 12, Folder 87)
    - Daily Sessions: November 19, 1961 (Box 12, Folder 88)
    - Daily Sessions: November 20, 1961 (Box 12, Folder 89)
    - Daily Sessions: November 21-22, 1961 (Box 13, Folder 90)
    - Daily Sessions: November 23-24, 1961 (Box 13, Folder 91)
    - Daily Sessions: November 25-27, 1961 (Box 13, Folder 92)
    - Daily Sessions: November 28, 1961 (Box 13, Folder 93)
    - Daily Sessions: November 30, 1961 (Box 13, Folder 94)
    - Daily Sessions: December 1-2, 1961 (Box 13, Folder 95)
    - Daily Sessions: December 3-5, 1961 (Box 13, Folder 96)
    - Executive Committee Report/ Central Committee Report, 1961 (Box 13, Folder 97)
    - Summaries and Slides/ Work Book/ Who's Who List of Participants, 1961 (Box 13, Folder 98)
    - Travel letters, 1961-1962 (Box 13, Folder 98A)
    - Handbook, 1961 (Box 67, Folder 461)
  - Fourth Assembly, Uppsala
    - Central Committee Report, Who's Who, Morning Worship, 1968 (Box 45, Folder 304)
    - Handbook, Drafts for sections, Visitors' Programme, 1968 (Box 67, Folder 462)
    - Workbook, Slide show text, Bible studies, 1968 (Box 67, Folder 463)
  - Fifth Assembly, Nairobi
    Originally scheduled to be held in Jakarta.
    - Preparatory Notes I-III, 1975 (Box 14, Folder 99)
    - Preparatory Notes IV-VI, 1975 (Box 14, Folder 100)
    - Workbooks, 1975 (Box 14, Folder 101)
    - Nairobi Notebook: Impressions and Reflections of R. L. Edwards/ Jesus Christ Frees and Unites / Uppsala to Nairobi: 1968-1975 Report of the Central Committee to the V Assembly of the WCC (Box 14, Folder 101A)
    - From Truk to Tonga: Migration and Development in the Pacific; study document for Nairobi, 1975 (Box 14, Folder 101B)
    - Community of Women and Men in the Church: a study by the WCC (working paper), 1975 (Box 67, Folder 464)
    - Section dossiers, 1975 (Box 69, Folder 477)
  - Sixth Assembly, Vancouver
    - Issues (Discussion papers)/ Ecumenical Press Service report, 24 July - 10 August 1983 (Box 48, Folder 333)
    - Jesus Christ - the Life of the World: A Worship Book for the Sixth Assembly of the WCC/ Work Book Vancouver 83/ Nairobi to Vancouver: 1975-1983, Report of the Central Committee to the Sixth Assembly of the WCC (Box 48, Folder 334)
    - Final report on the Theological Students conference at the Sixth Assembly, 1983 (Box 67, Folder 465)
  - Eighth Assembly, Harare
    - Welcome booklet, 1998 (Box 69, Folder 478)
  - Ninth Assembly, Porto Alegre
    - Brochure, 2006 (Box 69, Folder 479)
- Executive and Central Committee Meetings (1948-1987), Series III
  - General Secretariat
    - General, 1948-1949 (Box 15, Folder 101B)
  - Executive Committee
    - Reports
      - Geneva and Chichester, Geneva and TorontoParis and Rolle, London and unidentified; Geneva, Konigstein, 1949, 1950 1951, 1952 1953, 1954 (Box 15, Folder 102)
      - Geneva, 1955 (Box 15, Folder 103)
      - Gilbulla, 1956 (Box 15, Folder 104)
      - Vienna, 1956 (Box 15, Folder 105)
      - Geneva, 1957 (Box 15, Folder 106)
      - Greenwich, CT, 1957 (Box 15, Folder 107)
      - London, 1958 (Box 15, Folder 108)
      - Nyborg Strand, 1958 (Box 15, Folder 109)
      - Geneva, 1959 (Box 15, Folder 110)
      - Kifissia, 1959 (Box 15, Folder 111)
      - Buenos Aires, 1960 (Box 15, Folder 112)
      - St. Andrew's, 1950 (Box 15, Folder 113)
      - Geneva, 1951 (Box 15, Folder 114)
      - New Delhi, 1961 (Box 15, Folder 115)
      - Odessa, 1964 (Box 15, Folder 116)
    - Committee Records
      - Staffing Committee, 1956-1961 (Box 15, Folder 117)
  - Central Committee
    - Minutes and Reports
      - 1st Meeting, Amsterdam/Woudschoten, 1948 (Box 48, Folder 345)
      - 2nd Meeting, Chichester, 1949 (Box 48, Folder 345)
      - 3rd Meeting, Toronto, 1950 (Box 48, Folder 345)
      - 5th Meeting, Lucknow, 1953 (Box 48, Folder 345)
      - 6th and 7th Meetings, Chicago and Evanston, 1954, 1955 (Box 48, Folder 345)
      - 8th Meeting, Davos, 1955 (Box 50, Folder 345)
      - 9th Meeting, Galyatet, 1956 (Box 50, Folder 345)
      - 10th Meeting, New Haven, 1957 (Box 50, Folder 345)
      - 11th Meeting, Nyborg Strand, 1958 (Box 51, Folder 346)
      - 12th Meeting, Rhodes, 1959 (Box 51, Folder 346)
      - 13th Meeting, St. Andrew's, 1960 (Box 51, Folder 346)
      - 14th and 15th Meetings, New Delhi, 1961 (Box 51, Folder 346)
      - 16th Meeting, Paris, 1962 (Box 51, Folder 346)
      - 17th Meeting, Rochester, 1963 (Box 51, Folder 346)
      - 18th Meeting, Enugu, 1965 (Box 51, Folder 346)
      - 19th Meeting, Geneva, 1966 (Box 51, Folder 346)
      - 20th Meeting, Haraklion, 1967 (Box 51, Folder 346)
      - 21st and 22nd Meetings, Uppsala, 1968 (Box 51, Folder 346)
      - 23rd Meeting, Canterbury, 1969 (Box 51, Folder 346)
      - 24th Meeting, Addis Ababa, 1971 (Box 51, Folder 346)
      - 25th Meeting, Utrecht, 1972 (Box 51, Folder 346)
      - 26th Meeting, Geneva, 1973 (Box 52, Folder 347)
      - 27th Meeting, Berlin, 1974 (Box 52, Folder 347)
      - 28th Meeting, Nairobi, 1975 (Box 52, Folder 347)
      - 29th Meeting, Geneva, 1976 (Box 52, Folder 347)
      - 30th Meeting, Geneva, 1977 (Box 52, Folder 347)
      - 31st Meeting, Kingston, 1979 (Box 52, Folder 347)
      - 32nd Meeting, Geneva, 1980 (Box 52, Folder 347)
      - 33rd Meeting, Dresden, 1981 (Box 52, Folder 347)
      - 34th Meeting, Geneva, 1982 (Box 52, Folder 347)
      - 35th Meeting, Vancouver, 1983 (Box 52, Folder 347)
      - 36th Meeting, Geneva, 1984 (Box 52, Folder 347)
      - 37th Meeting, Buenos Aires, 1985 (Box 52, Folder 347)
      - 38th Meeting, Geneva, 1987 (Box 52, Folder 347)
    - Additional Documents
      - Amsterdam/Woudschoten, Chichester, 1948, 1949 (Box 16, Folder 118)
      - Toronto, 1950 (Box 16, Folder 119)
      - Rolle, 1951 (Box 16, Folder 120)
      - India, Evanston, 1952-53, 1954 (Box 16, Folder 121)
      - Davos, 1955 (Box 16, Folder 122)
      - Matrahaza (Galyatet), 1956 (Box 16, Folder 123)
      - New Haven: Organizational Materials, 1957 (Box 16, Folder 124)
      - New Haven: Numbered Documents, 1957 (Box 17, Folder 125)
      - New Haven: Documents, 1957 (Box 17, Folder 126)
      - New Haven: Worship, 1957 (Box 17, Folder 127)
      - New Haven: Press Clippings, 1957 (Box 17, Folder 128)
      - Nyborg Strand, 1958 (Box 17, Folder 129)
      - Rhodes: Documents 1-18, 1959 (Box 18, Folder 130)
      - Rhodes: Documents 19-46, 1959 (Box 18, Folder 131)
      - St. Andrew's: Correspondence, 1960 (Box 18, Folder 132)
      - St. Andrew's: Documents 1-24, 1960 (Box 18, Folder 133)
      - St. Andrew's: Documents 25-44, 1960 (Box 18, Folder 134)
      - St. Andrew's: Documents 45-51, 1960 (Box 18, Folder 135)
      - The Role of the WCC in International Affairs, 1986 (Box 18, Folder 135A)
      - Statement on the Middle East, 1967 (Box 67, Folder 466)
      - Memo. re. WCC Emergency Meeting on South Africa, 1985 (Box 69, Folder 480)
- Program Divisions, Commissions, Departments, Series IV
  - Christian Medical Commission
    - Miscellaneous, 1976, 1987 (Box 19, Folder 139)
  - The Churches Amid Racial and Ethnic Tension
    - Miscellaneous, 1957-1958 (Box 32, Folder 231A)
  - Commission of the Churches on International Affairs
    - Miscellaneous Publications, 1946-1961 (Box 20, Folder 141-146)
    - Miscellaneous Publications, 1962-1983 (Box 56, Folder 367-368)
    - Miscellaneous Publications, 1984-1987 1991-1994 (Box 57, Folder 388)
    - Reports, 1987-1990 (Box 67, Folder 470)
  - Commission on Faith and Order
    - World Conference on Faith and Order
    - First World Conference, Lausanne, 1927 (Box 21, Folder 147)
    - Second World Conference, Edinburgh, 1937 (Box 21, Folder 147A)
    - Third World Conference, Lund, 1952 (Box 67, Folder 467)
    - Fourth World Conference, Montreal, 1963 (Box 67, Folder 468)
    - World Conference on Faith and Order, Misc. meetings, reports, 1934-1948 (Box 58, Folder 396)
    - Theological Commission on the Church, 1949-1950 (Box 21, Folder 148, 149)
    - Miscellaneous Publications, 1949-1975 (Box 21, Folder 150-154)
    - Working paper from conference in Lima, Peru, 1982 (Box 21, Folder 154A)
    - Minutes, Amsterdam and Baarn, Holland meetings (New Series, No. 1), 1948 (Box 45, Folder 305)
    - Minutes, Chichester, England meeting (Paper No. 2), 1949 (Box 45, Folder 306)
    - Minutes, Clarens, Switzerland meeting (Paper No. 8), 1951 (Box 45, Folder 307)
    - Minutes, Lambeth Palace, London (Paper No. 9), 1952 (Box 45, Folder 308)
    - Minutes, Chateau de Bossey, Geneva (Paper No. 17), 1953 (Box 45, Folder 309)
    - Minutes, Evanston and Chicago, IL (Paper No. 21), 1954 (Box 45, Folder 310)
    - Minutes, Davos, Switzerland (Paper No. 22), 1955 (Box 45, Folder 311)
    - Minutes, Herrenalb, Germany (Paper No. 23), 1956 (Box 45, Folder 312)
    - Minutes, New Haven, CT (Paper No. 25), 1957 (Box 45, Folder 312A)
    - Minutes, Geneva, Switzerland (Paper No. 26), 1958 (Box 45, Folder 312B)
    - Minutes, Spittal, Austria (Paper No. 27), 1959 (Box 45, Folder 312C)
    - Minutes, St. Andrews, Scotland (Paper No. 31), 1960 (Box 65, Folder 421)
    - Minutes, Geneva, Switzerland (Paper No. 33), 1961 (Box 65, Folder 422)
    - Minutes, New Delhi, India and Paris France (Paper No. 36), 1961-1962 (Box 65, Folder 423)
    - Minutes, Montreal, Canada (Paper No. 41), 1963 (Box 65, Folder 424)
    - Minutes, Aarhus, Denmark (Paper No. 44), 1964 (Box 65, Folder 425)
    - Minutes, Bad Saarow, Germany (Paper No. 45), 1965 (Box 65, Folder 426)
    - Minutes, Zagorsk, USSR (Paper No. 48), 1966 (Box 65, Folder 427)
    - Minutes, Bristol, England (Paper No. 51), 1967 (Box 65, Folder 428)
    - Minutes, Uppsala and Sigtuna, Sweden (Paper No. 53), 1968 (Box 65, Folder 429)
    - Minutes, Canterbury, England (Paper No. 54), 1969 (Box 65, Folder 430)
    - Minutes, Louvain, Belgium (Paper No. 60), 1971 (Box 65, Folder 431)
    - Minutes, Utrecht, Holland (Paper No. 65), 1972 (Box 65, Folder 432)
    - Minutes, Zagorsk, USSR (Paper No. 66), 1973 (Box 65, Folder 433)
    - Minutes, Kloster Loccum, Germany (Paper No. 83), 1977 (Box 65, Folder 434)
    - Minutes, Bangalore, India (Paper No. 93), 1978 (Box 65, Folder 435)
    - Minutes, Taize, France (Paper No. 98), 1979 (Box 65, Folder 436)
    - Minutes, Annecy, France (Paper No. 106), 1981 (Box 65, Folder 437)
    - Lima, Peru: Vol. I, Minutes and Addresses (Paper No. 112); Vol. II, Study Papers and Reports (Paper No. 113), 1982 (Box 65, Folder 438)
    - Minutes, Crete, Greece (Paper No. 121), 1984 (Box 65, Folder 439)
    - Minutes, Potsdam, Germany (Paper No. 134), 1986 (Box 65, Folder 440)
    - Minutes, Madrid, Spain (Paper No. 141), 1987 (Box 65, Folder 441)
    - Minutes, Boston, Massachusetts (Paper No. 145), 1988 (Box 65, Folder 442)
    - Minutes, Dunblane, Scotland (Paper No. 152), 1990 (Box 66, Folder 443)
    - Minutes, Rome, Italy (Paper No. 157), 1991 (Box 66, Folder 444)
    - Minutes, Dublin, Ireland (Paper No. 158), 1992 (Box 66, Folder 445)
    - Minutes, Stuttgart, Germany (Paper No. 165), 1993 (Box 66, Folder 446)
    - Minutes, Cret-Berard, Switzerland (Paper No. 167), 1994 (Box 66, Folder 447)
    - Minutes, Aleppo, Syria (Paper No. 170), 1995 (Box 66, Folder 448)
    - Minutes, Bangkok, Thailand (Paper No. 172), 1996 (Box 66, Folder 449)
    - Minutes, Abbaye de Fontgombault, France (Paper No. 178), 1997 (Box 66, Folder 450)
    - Minutes, Matanzas, Cuba (Paper No. 188), 2000 (Box 66, Folder 450a)
    - Minutes, Gazzada, Italy (Paper No. 191), 2002 (Box 66, Folder 450b)
    - Statements and Reports: Faith and Order Papers #43, 56, 64, 68, 70, 73, 75 (Box 60, Folder 402)
    - Documents related to Oberlin meeting, 1957 (Box 60, Folder 401B)
    - Documents related to Louvain meeting: #59, 1971 (Box 60, Folder 401C)
    - Documents related to Accra meeting: #71, 72, 1974 (Box 60, Folder 401)
    - Joint Consultation on Biblical Hermeneutics (with Division of Studies), 1967 (Box 67, Folder 469)
  - Commission on Interchurch Aid, Refugee and World Service (see also: Department of Reconstruction and Interchurch Aid and Division of Interchurch Aid and Service to Refugees)
    - Miscellaneous Publications, 1959, 1975-1981 (Box 23, Folder 161A-161E)
  - Commission on the Churches' Participation in Development
    - Network Newsletter, 1981- (Box 43, Folder 291)
    - Activity Reports, 1972- (Box 43, Folder 292, 293)
    - Informational brochure; booklet: "Towards a Church in Solidarity with the Poor", 1980, n.d. (Box 67, Folder 471)
  - Commission on the Life and Work of Women in the Church
    - see also: Department on Cooperation of Men and Women in Church, (Family) and Society and Department on Women in Church and Society) (Box 27, Folder 191)
  - Commission on Proselytism and Religious Liberty
    - General, 1956 (Box 27, Folder 191A)
  - Commission on Religious Liberty
    - General (see also: Secretariat on Religious Liberty), 1958-1960 (Box 28, Folder 201B)
    - General, 1958-1960 (Box 28, Folder 201B)
  - Commission/Division on World Mission and Evangelism
    - General, 1959-1962 (Box 23, Folder 162)
  - Commission on World Mission and Evangelism
    - Miscellaneous publications (see also: Commission on Interchurch Aid), 1959-1962 (Box 23, Folder 162)
    - Miscellaneous Publications (incl. re. Theological Education Fund), 1963-1971, 1980 (Box 44, Folder 303A)
    - Miscellaneous Publications (incl. re. Urban Industrial Mission), 1971-1982, 1987 (Box 44, Folder 303B)
    - Miscellaneous Publications, 1983-1984 (Box 44, Folder 304)
    - WCC Mission Series, 1985-1987 (Box 58, Folder 392)
    - Urban Rural Mission newsletter, 1984- (Box 58, Folder 396)
    - Study documents, 1966 (Box 60, Folder 401A)
    - Monthly letter on evangelism, 1988 (Box 61, Folder 408)
    - Executive Committee minutes, 1975 (Box 70, Folder 481)
    - Preparatory papers for Athens meeting, 2005 (Box 70, Folder 482)
    - Athens conference materials, 2005 (Box 70, Folder 483-485)
  - Committee on the History of the Ecumenical Movement
    - General, 1951-1954 (Box 23, Folder 163)
  - Conference on Church and Society
    - General, n.d. (Box 23, Folder 164)
  - Department of Finance and Administration (includes material related to Geneva headquarters library)
    - General, 1956-1961 (Box 23, Folder 165)
  - Department of Information
    - Concept -Special issues 23, 25, 27, 31, n.d. (Box 24, Folder 166)
    - Concept -Special issues 33, 34, 39, 40, n.d. (Box 24, Folder 167)